《绿箭》前情回顾
Previously, on "Arrow"...
这座城市需要不是躲在面罩后的人挺身而出
This city needs someone to stand up who isn't hiding behind a mask.
■
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译
最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
她需要领导
It needs a leader.
所以  我要竞选市长
So, I decided to run for mayor.
奥利  这是艾利克斯·戴维斯
Ollie, this is Alex Davis,
翻译   Michael  SophiaSaaaga  Liv
沃尔特推荐的战略官
the new political strategist that Walter recommended.
在医院的时候  我看着莎拉的眼睛
At the hospital, I looked sara in the eyes.
翻译    Reginamoon  Silence   迷失星城
那不是她
She wasn't there.
我是之前杀她的那个人
I'm the one who killed her in the first place.
校对   Michale  Reginamoon  小闪迷路过
精校   陈小圈
这也是她追杀我的原因
That's why she's after me, you know.
驱使着她的这种杀戮的欲望
This blood lust she's consumed by...
跟我想到拉斯时候的感觉一样
It's the same pain I feel when I think about Ra's.
时间轴风吹来的那片云
她杀掉我后就会没事了
As soon as she kills me, she'll be OK.
后期   咖啡Lee    总监   苹果果
录音里似乎还有其他东西
Like there's more to the recording.
只是被覆盖了
Something overlapping with it.
我想告诉你的是
What I need you to know is,
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
我还活着  但我深陷困境
I'm alive, and I'm in trouble.
半年前
打开新文件
Open new file.
原子计划  伽马更新
Atom Project, Update Gamma.
这是第一次小型化测试
This will be miniaturization test number one.
执行
Execute.
为什么第一次总是不行呢
Why can't anything ever work the first time?
好吧  二位  我知道竞选计划
All right, guys, I know it's been a long haul
现在
耗时有点长了
figuring out your platform,
不过好消息是  我们快搞定了
but the good news is, we're almost done.
只有这两件事还需要考虑
Just two more things here on the docket.
其实  只有一件了
Actually, only one.
我想出来了在哪举办
I figured out where we're going to hold
奥利的资金筹集会
Ollie's fundraiser.
就在杰拉德办
It's going to be at Gerard's.
我记得那个地方收费挺高的
From what I remember, that place is a little pricey,
从而引出了我们要谈的最后一个话题
leading us to our last talking point,
预算
the budget.
你有预算了  对吧
You have it, right?
如果"你"是指费利西蒂的话
If by "you", you mean Felicity,
是的  她本来也应该来的
then, yes. She was supposed to be here,
可是她这几天很忙
but she's just been slammed
一直都待在帕尔默科技
at Palmer Tech for the past few days.
她当总裁当得很认真啊
She's really taking this whole CEO thing seriously.
我们俩总得有一个干挣钱的活啊
Well, one of us has to have a job that actually makes money.
我会去跟她谈的  然后把数字报给你
I'll speak with her, I'll get those numbers for you.
艾利克斯  非常感谢你的努力工作
Alex, thank you so much for all your hard work.
先走了
I'll see you later.
我在想
I was thinking,
或许我们明晚应该去杰拉德看看
maybe we should check out Gerard's tomorrow night.
确保那个地方适合我们
You know, just to make sure it's the right type of venue
介绍候选人
for introducing our candidate.
你这是在约我出去吗
Are you asking me out on a date?
说实话
To be honest,
我都好久没约会了  我也不知道了
it's been so long, I don't even know.
我只是  我现在的生活很乱
I just am-- my life is really complicated right now,
我觉得跟我哥哥的
And I don't think going on a date
竞选主管约会不会有什么好处
with my brother's campaign manager is going to make it any easier.
没错  你说得对  我太不专业了
No, you're right. That was totally unprofessional,
我从来不这样的
something I would normally never do.
我只是  觉得我们有感觉
I just... thought there was something there.
可能是因为吃了太多味精吧
Probably just consumed a little too much MSG.
我们就当刚才什么都没发生过吧
How about we just erase these last five minutes?
那不行
Absolutely not.
刚才很好
It was nice.
我出去了
I'll see you later.
我还活着
I'm alive,
但我深陷困境
and I'm in trouble.
我还活着  但我深陷困境
I'm alive, and I'm in trouble.
我还活着
I'm alive,
-我让你用我的实验室  -但我深陷困境
- I thought I said you could use my lab - and I'm in trouble.
前提是你用完得收拾干净
if you clean up after yourself.
关键词是"用完"  也就是我搞定了之后
The keyword being "after," which assumes finished,
但很显然  我还没搞定
which clearly, I am not.
那你弄得怎么样了
Well, how's it going?
这么棒
That well?
你是在循环播放吗
Do you have that playing on a loop?
我想追踪到雷的录音的源头
I've been trying to trace to Ray's message back to its point of origin,
可是这条信息经过了太多的服务器
but he must have ping-ponged it off of like a thousand servers,
而且追溯的算法也无法编译
and the back trace algorithm won't compile,
也就是说没办法找到他
which means there's no way of finding him,
你得停下了
You need to stop right now.
不行
I can't.
不行也得行
You have to.
你现在这种状态帮不了帕默尔先生
You are no good to Mr. Palmer in your current state.
你最近一次休息是什么时候
Now, how long has it been since you took a break?
我两个小时前睡了两分钟
I dozed off for about two minutes about an hour ago,
这算吗
does that count?
你结婚了  他是直男
You're married, he's straight,
you're married, he's straight.
太好了
Perfect.
奥利弗·奎恩  这是柯蒂斯·霍特
Oliver Queen, Curtis Holt.
柯蒂斯  这是奥利弗
Curtis, Oliver.
柯蒂斯  费利西蒂经常跟我说起你
Curtis! Felicity's told me a lot about you.
她基本上没跟我提过你
She's told me virtually nothing about you.
好吧
OK.
柯蒂斯
Curtis?
你在干什么
What you doing?
绿箭侠的出现
The Green Arrow showed up right about the time
正好在你回来以后
that you came back into town.
不过不是你  下巴不对
Nah, it's not you, though. Jaw's not right.
我一直都这么说
That's what I keep telling people.
能让我们单独谈谈吗
Would you give us a minute?
当然了  很高兴见到你
Sure thing. Nice meeting you.
我也很高兴见到你
Nice meeting you, too.
你不是说好要去竞选办公室
I thought that you were going to come by the campaign offices
谈预算方面的事吗
to go over the finances.
不是定在周三吗
I thought that meeting was on Wednesday.
今天就是周三
It is wednesday.
怎么了
What's going on?
我还活着  但我深陷困境
I'm alive, and I'm in trouble.
这好像是...
That sounds like...
雷  因为这就是雷
Ray. Because it is ray,
雷还没死
Because Ray isn't dead.
什么  这不可能  雷...
What? That's impossible. Ray was...
已经死了  死于半年前的一次爆炸
Killed. In an explosion that blew up
还把这座楼的楼顶炸毁了
the top of this building six months ago.
可很显然事情不是那样的
But that's obviously not what happened,
因为他在六天前发送了这条消息
because he sent this message six days ago,
而死了的人一般是做不到的
and dead people don't generally do that.
雷还活着  他就在某个地方
Ray's alive. He's out there somewhere.
我必须要帮他
I have to help him,
你为什么之前没跟我们说过这个地方
Why didn't you ever tell us about this place before?
我不知道是在这里
I didn't know it was here.
不过你似乎知道
But it sort of seems like you did.
我知道这座岛不像它看起来那样
I know this island isn't all that it seems.
你做得很好  奎恩先生
You've done well, Mr. Queen.
可是你让那个英国佬跑掉了
But you let the British guy get away.
等一下  瑞特
Wait. Reiter.
康斯坦丁说这里有某种
Constantine said that there was some sort of
障碍物  就像是魔法
barrier, like magic.
我对里面不感兴趣
I have no interest in the chamber.
这是什么
What is that?
信息  很久以前的信息
A message, from the ancients,
指向一种很特别的东西
Leading to a very special gift.
水之心
A heart of water.
你在岛上见过小湾吗
Have you seen a cove on the island,
周围有山环绕
Surrounded by mountains?
是的  我知道有一处
Yeah, I know of one.
你带人去那里挖掘
I want you to go to that point and lead an excavation.
带上十几个劳力  直到挖到
Take a dozen of the laborers and work them
我要的东西为止
until you find my gift.
我能跟你谈谈吗
Can I talk to you for a sec?
首先
All right, first,
这里的事情你还有什么没告诉我
what aren't you telling m about what we're doing here?
除了所有这些之外
I mean, apart from everything.
其次呢
And second?
奎恩是内鬼
Queen is a mole.
不要因为他给了你那玩意就相信他了
Don't start trusting him just 'cause he gave you a piece of bling.
陪奎恩先生一起去小湾
Accompany Mr. Queen to the cove.
我知道
I know.
我也爱你  妈妈
I love you, too, mom.
我非常爱你
I love you so much.
好的  再见  妈妈
OK, bye, Mom.
聊得怎么样
How'd that go?
比起上次妈妈发现我活着  这次容易多了
Easier than the last time Mom found out that I wasn't dead.
你还好吗  亲爱的
You ok, honey?
挺好的  只是妈妈跟我讲
Yeah, fine. It was just something mom said
有次我放学回家迷路了
about how I got lost when I was walking home from school once,
然后我跟她保证我一定会回家
and--and how I promised that I'd always come back.
但是我记不得这事了
But I can't remember.
不记得从前父母对我们做过的
You're probably better off not remembering
那些一团糟的事  你可能会过得更好
all the messed up things our parents did to us, anyway.
你俩现在挺好的
Hey, you two turned out perfectly, all right,
更重要的是  你们都回家了
and more importantly, you're both home.
我别无他求了
I couldn't ask for anything more.
我告诉你雷有麻烦  你第一反应却是
I tell you Ray's in trouble and your first response is,
"你该洗澡了"
you need a shower.
还该补个觉
And a nap.
你帮不了...
You're not going to be able to help--
停   你的语气像柯蒂斯
Oh, stop. You're starting to sound like Curtis.
柯蒂斯是个聪明人
Well, Curtis is a smart guy.
雷的信息有暗示他的困难是什么吗
Did Ray's message indicate what kind of trouble he's in?
如果有  我早就告诉你了
If it did, it would have been the first thing I told you.
那有什么我能帮忙的吗
Ok. Is there anything that I can do to help?
你这三天有突然学会编程吗
Well, have you magically learned to code in the last 72 hours?
没
No.
这是个反问
It was a rhetorical question.
我知道
I know.
但是  我愿意
I will, however,
接受你坚定不移的帮助和按摩
accept your undying support and backrub.
你可以两者兼有  只要你去...
You can have both as soon as you...
洗澡
Shower.
还有补一觉
And take a nap.
去吧
Come on.
快去  快去
Come on, come on.
怎么了
What?
我设置了当跟踪程序完成编译
I set an alert just in case the back trace program
就给我发送提示
ever finished compiling.
费利西蒂
Felicity...
给我两秒钟
Two seconds!
已经等那么久了
It's been taking forever.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
我什么也没做
Absolutely nothing.
费利西蒂  费利西蒂  是你吗
Felicity, Felicity, is that you?
我的天  雷
Oh, my God, Ray!
雷  你在哪里
Ray, where are you?
我不知道
I don't know.
说得详细点
And if that wasn't enough,
我是被劫持了
I think I'm being held against my will.
什么
What?!
他们要我的装备  至少是要我的技术
Yeah, they want my suit, or at least the tech.
好消息是  我的技术
The good news is, the tech is
此刻对他们没用
useless to them in my current condition.
雷  如果你的衣服在身边
Ray, if you have your suit,
那干嘛不直接...
then why don't you just--
冲出去吗  不管用
Bust my way out? Yeah, that's not really happening.
什么  装备不管用吗
What, the suit doesn't work?
事实上  是太管用了
Actually, it worked a little too well.
绿 箭
第四季  第六集
他们要我的装备  至少是要我的技术
They want my suit, or at least the tech.
好消息是  我的技术
The only good news is, the tech is useless to them
此刻对他们没用
in my current condition.
约翰绝不会相信这事
John is never going to believe this.
西娅也不会信
Neither is Thea.
雷他...
And, well, Ray is--
变成了薯块那么大
the size of a tater tot.
雷用他被冒牌绿箭射之后我给他注射的
Ray modified his suit with the same nanites
纳米科技改良了他的装备
I injected into him after bad Arrow shot him.
说来话长  还涉及很多分子物理
It's a long story involving a lot of molecular physics.
重要的是我们知道雷
The bottom line is that Ray
紧急给我发来了一条短程消息
jury-rigged a short-range message burst
但被劫持他的人拦截了
that was intercepted by whoever's holding him captive.
雷认为他们想要装备  以盗取其技术
Ray thinks they want the suit for its technology,
但是它现在太小了  他们没法用
but they can't use it while its small.
雷现在很小  要找到他简直是
And while he's small, it's like looking for a needle
海底捞针
in a city of haystacks.
雷有样东西  他觉得能帮上忙
Ray has something he thinks could help.
在帕尔默科技  有一幅能把我变回
Back at Palmer Tech, I've got schematics for a machine
原来大小的机器原理图
that should be able to resize me.
现在你们都知道了
Well, now that you're both filled in...
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
去帕尔默科技拿雷的装备原理图
To Palmer Tech to pull up the schematics for Ray's device.
我跟你一起去
I'll come with you.
为什么  你会造出那东西吗
Why? Are you going to build the thing?
不会
No.
但我能在别处帮上忙
There must be some other way I can help.
不需要
There isn't.
事情还没结束
This isn't over, you know.
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
我们之间的事
You and me.
我很高兴
I'm so glad.
我们要让一些人下水
We need to get a couple people in the water.
潜下去  找找下面有什么
Dive down, see what you can find.
大家都累了  都劳动好几个小时了
Everyone is tired. We've been here for hours.
你要是想让他们工作
If you want them to work,
他们也得有力气工作才行
they have to be able to.
你是他们的领导吗
Are you their leader?
我叫你让他们休息
I'm the guy telling you to let them rest.
行
Ok.
你们带了食物
You brought food.
休息十五分钟吃点吧
Take 15 minutes and eat.
你还真是本月最佳雇主
Well, ain't you employer of the month.
你帮我盯着他们点
I'm going to need you to keep an eye on them,
我要去安安静静地吃个午饭
and I'm going to go enjoy my lunch in peace.
你  乌克兰人
Hey, Ukraine.
我叫瓦勒徳
My name is Vlad.
行  瓦勒徳
Well, Vlad,
想不想让你的日子好过点
how'd you like your life to get a little better?
帕尔默博士实现了微型技术
Doctor Palmer got miniaturization to work.
他在原子收缩领域作出了重大突破
He made the space between atoms shrink.
这就好像解决冷聚变和终极理论
I mean, this is like solving cold fusion and ultimate theory.
你知道这有多神奇吗
Do you have any idea how amazing this is?
知道  但事实是雷被劫持
Yes. But the fact that Ray is being held hostage
随时都可能被杀
and could be killed at any moment
他缩小到芝士条那么大  我开心不起来
because he is the size of a Cheeto has dampened my enthusiasm somewhat.
你能造出这个来吗
Can you build this?
能  所需的材料帕尔默科技都有
Yes. Um, all the materials are here at Palmer Tech,
除了这个
um, except for that.
这是个量子集合管
That is a quantum manifold.
没听说过  在哪能找到这个
Never heard of it. Where do we get one?
只有一个地方  制造厂
Only one place-- the manufacturer.
他们申请了专利...十六项专利
They hold the patent on it-- well, actually, 16 patents.
哪里
Where?!
科尔德实业
Kord Industries.
我本想让他们帮个忙
I'd ask them to do us a solid
把它借给我们  但...
and loan it to us, but...
他们是我们最大的竞争对手
They're our biggest competitor.
好在事情已经不会更糟了
The good news is, things can't get any worse.
谁说不会
You just had to go and say that.
你真的在这里
There you are!
妈妈
Mom.
你来做什么
Oh, what are you doing here?
我去了你的办公室  总裁小姐
Well, I went to your office, Miss CEO,
你助理告诉我你可能在这里
and your assistant told me you'd be here.
于是...我就来这里了
So...here I am.
我不是指这里  是指星城
Not here-here, Star City here.
奥利弗告诉我你这几个月一直在
Well, Oliver told me that you've been working
不停工作  所以我提议说你会需要
nonstop this past month, so I suggested a visit from your mom
妈妈来看看你  你猜怎么着
is exactly what you needed, and guess what?
怎么着
What?
他同意了
He agreed.
你是哪位
And who are you?
您好
Hi.
我叫柯蒂斯·霍特
I'm Curtis Holt.
见到您真开心
It is an absolute pleasure to meet you.
我明白了费利西蒂为什么...
I can see where Felicity got her, uh...
有一头金发
Blonde hair.
其实  她的头发是染的
Well, she dyes it, actually.
你想先做什么呢
So, what do you want to do first?
去商场  做指甲彩绘
A trip to the mall, mani-pedi.
舟车劳顿  你现在一定很累
You know what, you must be exhausted from your flight.
我叫车送你去我的住处吧
Why don't I get a car to take you back to my place?
叫车
A car?
不  宝贝  我来就是为了见你
No, baby, I-- I came here to see you.
我知道  你还能再见到我的
I know! And you will.
只是  现在柯蒂斯和我正在试图搞清楚
It's just that, right now, curtis and I are trying to figure out
如何造一个非常重要的设备
how to build a very important piece of equipment,
不然有人会死
or someone could die.
-死  -只是打个比方
- Die? - Metaphorically speaking!
你开始造那个机器
You start constructing the machine,
然后我会把集合管给你找来
and I will get you the manifold.
但那是别人的专利  你要怎么搞到
But it's proprietary! How are you going to do that?
不是我去
I'm not!
真棒
Awesome.
绿箭侠今晚得出去露一手了
The Green Arrow's going to be kicking some ass tonight.
假如我没先对他露一手
If I don't kick his first.
科尔德实业
我还以为那会是件好事呢
I thought it would be a good thing.
好事
A good thing?
你到底为什么会同意她来啊
What on earth made you agree to this?
你也知道  你妈不太接受别人的拒绝
Well, you know, your mom doesn't really take no for an answer.
你直面过
You've faced down
米拉库鲁士兵和刺客联盟
Mirakuru soldiers and the League of Assassins.
你真的想说你无法拒绝我妈吗
are you honestly telling me that you couldn't say no to my mom?
她说她想你了  然后给我短信了个
She said she missed you and then she texted me
流了一滴泪的表情
one of those emojis with the single tear.
你居然和我妈发短信
You have been texting with my mother?!
什么时候开始的
How long has that been going on?
你们可以另找时间吵这件事吗
You guys think we can find a better time to fight about this?
约翰
John?
我还以为只有奥利弗的线是开着的
I thought only Oliver's line was open.
不  我的也开了
Nope. Mine is open.
还有我的
And mine.
我都不记得任务中有这么多闲聊了
I don't remember there being so much chatter on these missions.
你还好吧
Are you ok?
还好
Yeah.
我需要正常点的生活
I need a little normal.
对我而言  这才是正常的生活
And for me, this is the kind of thing that passes.
我黑进了安全面板
I hacked the security panel,
但是必须要到里面才能接入
but it needs to be accessed from the inside.
唯一的问题是那栋建筑的内部
Only problem is that the building's interior
受压力感应地板的保护
is protected by pressure sensitive flooring,
这意味着多嘴凯西  该你上了
which means Chatty Kathy, you're up.
-多嘴凯西  -你的新代号
- Chatty Kathy? - Your new code name,
唯一一个我能想到的  适当的
the only one appropriate enough I could think of
文雅的外号
to use in polite company.
一旦装卸区的门打开了
Once the loading dock's doors are open,
你们有90秒的时间找到集合管
you'll have 90 seconds to find the manifold
并且在武装警卫来之前撤离
and amscray before men with guns show up.
多嘴凯西
Chatty Kathy?
等我回去后
You know, when I get back,
你和我得好好谈谈了
you and I are going to have a talk.
我到面板处了
I'm at the panel.
等着
Stand by.
输入  4  5  8  7
Punch in 4, 5, 8, 7.
90秒  时间不等人
90 seconds, clock's running.
你确定带莎拉一起来是个好主意吗
Are you sure it was a good idea to bring Sara along?
她会没事的
She'll be fine.
出问题了
Something's wrong.
监控摄像头正在恢复
The security cameras are coming back online.
我来搞定
I've got it.
不  你还不明白吗
No, don't you understand?!
假如科尔德升级了他们的安保系统
If Kord upgraded their security,
他们八成也缩短了反应时间
they probably improved their response time.
等等  我觉得就是这个
Wait, I think this is it.
莎拉  住手
Sara, stop!
莎拉
Sara!
我们得走了
We have to go.
我们安全了
We're clear.
喂
Hello?
有人在吗
Is anyone there?
雷...
Ray...
研究好原理图了吗
Any luck with the schematics?
我意识到了量子集合管可能比较难搞到
I realize the quantum manifold could present a challenge.
任何问题只要去科尔德实业来一趟
Nothing a little late night shopping
深夜小采购都能解决
at Kord Industries couldn't solve.
太棒了  谢谢你  费利西蒂
Oh, that's great. Thank you, Felicity.
现在我们只需要弄清楚如何...
Now we just have to figure out how to--
雷  你还在吗
Ray, you still there?
不
Oh, no.
你们出任务的时候发生什么事了
What happened out there?
莎拉  她...
Sara, she, um...
对保安大打出手
had a moment with the security guard.
劳蕾尔和西娅带她回家了
Laurel and Thea took her home.
你确定你在雷的摄像头中看到的是达克吗
Are you sure it was Darhk that you saw in Ray's camera?
和我确定雷在劫难逃一样确定
Just as sure as I am that Ray is not getting out of this!
雷在达克手里其实是件好事
It's actually good that Darhk has Ray.
这和你认为我妈过来会让我好受点
This would be the same level of delusion that made you think
是用一个级别的错觉吗
my mother coming to town would make me feel better?
既然是达克  那意味着我们有个优势
Because it's Darhk, that means that we have an asset.
兰斯
Lance.
我会叫他帮我们弄到地址
I'll ask him to get us a location.
假如忽然之间
And what if between then and now,
达克决定用脚碾死雷呢
Darhk decides to squish Ray underneath his shoe?
假如达克想要伤害雷  他早就下手了
If Darhk wanted to hurt Ray, he would have done it by now.
狄格说得对  我们集中精力
Dig's right. We stay focused.
我们帮柯蒂斯搞到集合管
We get Curtis the manifold,
让他继续努力
keep him working,
然后很不幸我们只能
and we unfortunately just have to wait
等兰斯找出地址
and see what Lance finds out.
我讨厌等待的感觉
I hate waiting and seeing.
我必须得做些什么
I have to do something.
你妈妈过来了  花点时间陪她
Your mother's in town, spend some time with her.
我们可以一起吃晚饭  我来做饭
We could do dinner. I'll cook.
你已经和我妈定好吃晚餐了  是不是
You already made dinner plans with my mother, didn't you?
什么  没有
What? No.
是的
Yes.
天呐
Oh! Oh, my God!
你是不是有病啊
It is like a sickness with you!
我不是故意的  我们当时聊得挺愉快
It wasn't intentional. We were having a nice conversation;
话题转到了烹饪上
the subject turned to cooking,
我说起我做的奶酪鸡排可好吃了
I mentioned that I make a spectacular chicken cordon bleu.
她说她从来没吃过  只是吃顿饭而已
She said she'd never had one. It's just dinner.
他说得对  费利西蒂
He's right, Felicity.
再说了  你看起来很久没...
Besides, you look like you haven't...
吃饭或睡觉了
eaten or slept.
一个人的生命
A man's life,
一个朋友的生命  危在旦夕
a friend's life is in danger.
不像是个吃奶酪鸡排的好时机
Doesn't seem like the right time for cordon bleu.
我发誓在兰斯和柯蒂斯搞定前
I promise you that there is nothing that we can do
我们什么也做不了
until we get what we need from Lance and Curtis.
所以  吃个晚餐吧
So, dinner.
晚上七点  我一和兰斯谈完就赶过去
7:00 pm. I'll be there as soon as I'm done with Lance.
反应敏捷
Nice instincts.
我之前不确定你会回来
I wasn't sure you were coming back.
我说过我会的
Well...I said that I would.
我猜你也不会觉得惊讶
I guess it's no surprise to you,
但我已经对人们履行自己所承诺之事
but I have lost faith in people doing
丧失了信心
what they said they're going to do.
你有注意到除了营地和毒品以外
Do you notice Reiter interested in anything other
瑞特还对其他什么东西感兴趣吗
than the camp or drugs?
有
Yeah.
他还很喜欢拆散别人的家庭
He also enjoys stealing people away from their families.
你有见过他做某些...神秘的
Well, have you seen him do anything, uh, mystical,
甚至是...有魔法的事吗
or even... magical?
他一直有点奇怪
He always has been a little odd.
他还非常的虔诚
And very religious.
他甚至给一些囚犯赐福
He's even blessed some of the prisoners.
声称自己治愈了他们的灵魂之类的疯话
Claims he's healed their souls or some craziness.
我开始觉得
I'm beginning to think
毒品只是他在此处的真正目的的幌子
that drugs are just a front for what he's really doing here.
对他这种人而言还有什么比金钱更能诱惑他呢
What could be more tempting to a man like him than money?
权力
Power.
我不能待太久
I can't stay long.
康克林已经对我起疑
I can't have Conklin being any more
我不能让他疑心更重了
suspicious of me than he already is,
但你还是得待在这里
but you still need to stay here.
我会尽量多过来
I'll come back as much as I can.
这一次  我信你
This time, I believe you.
好久不见了
Heh, I thought it was past time that we met.
我的工程师失败了
My engineers have had no
无法把你恢复回原来的大小
success in restoring you to your proper size,
所以我决定要跟你合作
so I thought I'd appeal to your cooperation.
帮了你我能得到什么
And what do I get if I help you out?
除了会死这个可能以外
Apart from probably death.
不
No.
你该担心的不是你的性命
I don't think it's your life you should be worried about.
对不起  费利西蒂  这是我的错
I'm sorry, Felicity, this is my fault.
谁是费利西蒂呢
And who is this "Felicity," I wonder?
肯定不是你的前任副总裁
Certainly not your former vice-president,
现任总裁  女朋友
current CEO, girlfriend.
你敢碰她试试
Don't you touch her.
别做无用的威胁
Don't make empty threats.
这
It's...
很渺小
small.
顺带一句
And by the way,
我们本没打算听到一个死人的呼救
we weren't listening for a distress call from a dead man.
我们截获了你的信息  纯属运气
It was pure luck, really, that we intercepted your message.
但运气不就是命运的代名词吗
But isn't luck just another word for destiny?
抱歉我来迟了
Sorry I'm late.
我尽量照配方来做
I, um, I tried following the recipe,
但是我想你的烤炉可能坏了
but, you know, I think your oven might be broken,
因为我本该把鸡放进去烤二十分钟左右
because I was supposed to put in for like 20 minutes,
然后不知怎么
and, I don't know,
它就突然冒烟了
smoke just started billowing out,
我想鸡烤得还不是
and I think the chicken's just a little,
很熟
slightly undercooked.
严格来说就是生的
I think the technical term is raw.
没事  没事
It's-- it's fine, it's fine.
我已经回来了  我很快就能搞定
I'm home now. I'll whip something up.
因为你总是能解决一切问题
'Cause you just always fix everything.
会做菜的男人
A man who cooks.
要用戒指来套住他
You put a ring on that.
那个非常重要的医生预约怎么样  亲爱的
How'd that very important doctor's appointment go, hon?
还不错
Uh, good, yes.
兰斯医生只是要检查一下
Dr. Lance is just going to find out
疼痛的来源
where the pain is coming from.
疼痛  你没事吧  亲爱的
Pain? You ok, hon?
没事  我只是想搞清楚我做错了什么
Fine. I'm just trying to figure out what I've done wrong.
我
I...
我去买点外卖
I'm going to go get some take-out.
吵完架后做爱是最美好的了
The best part about arguing is the make-up sex.
好吧
Ok.
邀请你妈妈突然造访是个坏主意
Inviting your mother for a surprise visit wasn't the best idea.
我完全同意
I totally accept that.
可我不同意或不明白的是
What I'm not accepting, or understanding,
你完全不对我敞开心扉
is just you shutting me out.
我没有不对你敞开心扉
I am not shutting you out.
我想要集中注意力找到雷
I'm trying to focus on finding Ray,
但这些事分散了我的注意力
but I can't do that with all of these distractions.
分散你的注意力  你怎么了
Distractions? What is going on with you?
你表现得好像是我害雷...
You're acting like it's my fault that Ray--
是我的错
It's my fault.
发生在雷身上的事
What's happening with Ray--
他发生的事都是我的错
to Ray-- is my fault.
费利西蒂  真的不是这样
Felicity, it really isn't.
事故发生后  雷连续几周一直发来求救信号
Ray was sending distress calls for weeks after the accident.
我不在这里  所以没接收到
I wasn't here to receive them
因为我忙于和你周游世界
because I was too busy traveling the world with you.
我拿走了语音记录  导致没人发现
I took the voice's word for it that no body could be recovered
我沉浸在和你一起的时光里
because I was so swept up in being with you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
是我自己选择离开我的整个生活
It was my choice to uproot my entire life,
离开家和工作  放弃了我擅长的事情
leave my home and my job, which turns out, I am very good at.
我在你身上迷失了自己
I lost myself in you,
我再也不是当初的我了
and I was never that girl.
我完全迷失在一个男人身上
That girl who just loses herself in a guy.
我不是这样的人
That is not who I am.
这和雷无关
This isn't about Ray.
而是我们俩
It's about us.
不
No.
是的
Yes.
我也不知道
I don't know.
好吧
Ok.
在你理清头绪之前  我给你一点空间
I'm going to give you some space until you figure it out.
这里显示交通摄像头连网了
It says the traffic cameras are online.
是的  等一会才会上载
Yeah, you got to give it a minute to upload.
你怎么来了
What are you doing here, anyway?
我还以为我负责等兰斯
I thought I was waiting for Lance
而你和两位斯莫克女士去吃晚饭
and you were having dinner with the Smoak ladies.
吃得这么顺利啊
Went that well, did it?
你知道我想念我们以前工作室的什么吗
Do you know what I miss about our old space?
想念那个装有一瓶俄罗斯伏特加的箱子
That trunk, with the bottle of Russian vodka in it.
伏特加
Vodka...
是给没用的人喝的
is for wimps, anyway.
伏特加给没用的人喝
Vodka is for wimps?
田纳西威士忌
Tennessee whiskey.
来点猛的吧
Put some hair on your chest.
很难想象和费利西蒂  还有她妈妈共进晚餐
It's hard to imagine dinner with Felicity and her mother
会不顺利
not going well.
问题不在唐娜身上
Donna's not the problem.
在我身上
I am.
费利西蒂说她在我们的关系里迷失了自我
Felicity says that she's lost herself in our relationship,
这意味着她不知道自己是谁
which means that she doesn't know who she is,
如果我们当初没有离开星城
and that if we hadn't have left Star City when we did,
她就能在这帮助雷
she would have been around to help Ray.
超能力者  魔法  死而复生
Metahumans, magic, resurrections--
我以为我都见识过了
I thought I'd seen it all,
但是奥利弗·奎恩吃醋
but Oliver Queen jealous?
我没吃醋  我只是要知道
I'm not jealous. I just got to know
去常春藤镇是否是正确的决定
if Ivy Town was as good as it gets for us,
因为我们已经回来了
because we've come back here.
所有的事就变得超级复杂
Everything has just gotten super complicated,
不禁让我想知道
and it just makes me wonder,
她为什么选择了我
why did she choose me?
奥利弗  这几年我听你说过很多疯狂的事
Oliver, I've heard you say a lot of crazy things over the years,
但这肯定是最疯狂的
but that has to be the prize.
你知道我的意思
You know what I mean.
我要十分钟才能登录这玩意
It takes me ten minutes to log into this thing;
费莉西蒂两秒钟就搞定
Felicity does it in two seconds,
而雷说不定发明了这东西
and Ray probably invented it.
你也许说得对
Yeah, you're probably right.
但是费利西蒂并没选择雷
Except, Felicity didn't choose Ray.
她选择了你
She chose you.
当然  她和雷有很多共同之处
Sure, she has a lot in common with Ray,
但是有时
but sometimes what looks
美好的理论并不适用于生活中
good on paper isn't what works in real life.
如果他真的遇到不测
What if something happens to him?
我们无法把他救回来
We don't get him back?
费利西蒂·斯莫克是这个地球上
Felicity Smoak is one of the smartest,
最聪明  最厉害的女人之一
most bad ass women on the planet.
她会达到目的  救回雷的
She comes through this, she'll get Ray back.
你好像很肯定
You seem pretty sure.
我就娶了一个这样的女人
I married a woman just like that.
还是两次  奥利弗  两次
Twice, Oliver, twice.
没错
Yes, you did.
感情总是跌宕起伏的
Look, man, relationships have their ups and downs.
有时要给对方一点时间
Sometimes you just have to give it some time,
一点空间
a little bit of space.
是兰斯
It's Lance.
二十分钟后和达克见面
Meeting with Darhk in 20.
你还好吗
You good?
好多了
Better.
谢谢你
Thank you.
田纳西    威士忌
搞什么
What the hell?!
很感谢你来见我
Appreciate you meeting me.
我知道你很忙
I know you're a busy man.
没错
I am.
但是我可能有办法让这座城市变得有用
But I may have found a way to make this city useful for once.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你会的
Oh, you will.
这座城市的每个人都会
Everyone in this city will.
也许我能比其他人早点明白
Well, maybe I could find out sooner than others.
我的女儿莎拉  她复活了
My daughter, Sara, she's, uh, she's back,
但并没有完全恢复
but, you know, not all the way.
她有些地方仍然不太正常
Something about her is still a little off.
老实说  我不懂这跟我有何关系
I assure you, the relevance escapes me.
我在想  也许我能多帮你一点
Well, I was thinking, maybe if I could help you a little more,
然后或许你也能帮回我
then maybe you could help me.
你知道怎么解决这些神神叨叨的事
You know your way around this magic mumbo jumbo.
神神叨叨
Mumbo jumbo?
我会考虑的  队长
I'll consider it, Captain,
但这是你最后一次召唤我
but this will be the last time you summon me.
约翰  他刚走
John, he just left.
正前往南面的维多利亚大街方向
He's heading south down Victoria Street.
收到
Copy that.
我正盯着呢
I've got eyes on that.
什么事
Yeah?
我给你拿了杯热牛奶
I brought you some hot milk.
我不是小孩了  妈妈
I'm not ten, Mom.
那我拿下楼去了
I'll bring it back downstairs.
别  等等
No, wait, wait, wait.
既然弄了就拿来吧
Since you went to all the trouble.
还记得你小的时候
Do you remember when you were a little girl
我告诉你不能去太空夏令营的事吗
and I told you you couldn't go to Space Camp?
你把自己锁在房里两天不出来
You locked yourself in your room for two days.
公平点说  那可是太空夏令营啊
Well, to be fair, it was Space Camp.
但我跟你说  我无法忍受
But I told you, I couldn't bear the thought
把你送去那么远待上两个月
of sending you away for eight weeks.
事实是  宝贝  我...
The truth was, hon, I...
我付不起钱
I couldn't afford it.
你为什么不直接告诉我呢
Then why didn't you just tell me that?
因为我为自己没钱而感到羞愧
Because, I was embarrassed, you know, that I had no money;
也不知道你父亲在哪
that I had no idea where your father was,
即使知道  他也不会付一份钱的抚养费
and even if I did, he never paid a dime in child support, anyway.
对不起  我不知道
I'm sorry. I had no idea.
我把所有都给了你父亲
I put everything into your father.
我的爱  我的信任和我的青春
My love, my trust, my twenties.
我想说的是  你...
My point is, you...
跟我不一样
are not me.
你拥有
You are the CEO
一个价值数千万的公司
of a bajillion dollar company.
而奥利弗  他跟你父亲不一样  宝贝
And Oliver, he's not like your father, hon.
他爱你
He loves you.
没有人用他看你那样的眼神看过我
No one has ever looked at me the way he looks at you.
他真的很好
He's wonderful.
每个方面都很好
In a million different ways.
但那正是问题所在
But that's the problem.
太容易为他而迷失自己了
It's too easy to lose myself in him.
宝贝
Baby.
当你爱一个人的时候
That's how it's supposed to feel
就应该是那样的感觉
when you love someone.
不管你信不信
Believe it or not,
他已经爱你爱得迷失自己了
he's lost himself in you.
而你们会在彼此身上
And you'll find yourself
找回自我的
in each other.
但别自己阻碍了自己
Just don't get in your own way.
也别毁了这些
And don't ruin something
大多数人根本无法得到的东西
that most people never get.
因为如果你放弃了  相信我
'Cause if you do, trust me,
你别想再找到个那么帅还会做饭的男人
you'll never find another guy that hot again, who cooks.
奥利弗
狄格找到雷了
谢谢
Thanks.
他绝对在那藏了什么
He is definitely hiding something in there.
拉丁大楼  城市陷落前
Latin Building. Before the city went to crap,
它被誉为西海岸最安全的大楼
it was touted as the most secure building on the west coast.
每个入口都由视网膜扫描仪
Every access point is protected by a retinal scanner,
和声纹识别系统保护
and a voice print.
我们不可能进得去
There is no way we're getting in there.
至少从外面不可能
Well, not from the outside, at least.
柯蒂斯的放大装置研究得怎么样了
How's Curtis doing on the resizing device?
他说能在一小时内让其运作起来
He said he could have something functional in an hour.
我认为我们没那么多时间
I don't think we have that kind of time.
他必须现场把装备组装起来
He's going to have to assemble it in the field.
等等  跟我们一起吗
Wait, with us?
真要让你的助理参与此事吗
Are we sure we want to have your assistant in on this?
他只是我的雇员  而我不确定我公司的
It's my employee, actually. And I'm not sure our company
健康保险能涵盖这么严重的事故
health plan covers supernatural dismemberment.
我们需要他
We need him.
如果柯蒂斯能在内部把雷变回去
And if Curtis can re-size Ray on the inside,
那我们就能多一个帮手逃出来
then we have another hand getting us all outside.
再多一个如何
Then how about one more?
我认为那不是个好主意
I don't think that's a good idea.
劳蕾尔  我不知道自己怎么了
Laurel, I don't know what's going on with me,
但我需要知道自己可以控制这个
but I need to know that I can control this.
着装准备
Suit up.
这些东西非常好
These are very nice.
你下去吧
Leave us.
包裹已送到
Package is delivered.
准备好了
Ready.
费利西蒂
Felicity?
准备好了
Ready.
从没准备得这么好
Or as ready as I'll ever be.
当我跟人事主管说想让工作更刺激点的时候
When I told HR I wanted a little bit more excitement from my job,
我所想的真的不是这样
this really isn't what I had in mind.
是你说想帮助雷的
You were the one who said you wanted to help Ray
而且你还说自己定点跳伞的技术很高超
and that you were an accomplished base jumper.
天呐  我的爱好真的太多了
Oh, God, I really do have too many hobbies.
好了  视死如归的英雄们  开始吧
All right, Spartan, let's do this.
视死如归
Spartan?
我们今晚有客人了
We have a guest tonight.
好了  解除安保系统...
All right, disengaging security systems...
现在
Now.
你俩没事吧
You two ok?
我们没死
We're not dead.
很好
Good.
行动
Let's go.
你介意我...偷看一下吗
You mind if I take a little...peeks?
当然了  我也有自己的猜疑
I mean, I have my suspicions, of course.
但我只是想知道那是否正确  如往常一样
But I just want to see if I'm right, as usual.
刚才的交手中你什么也没学到吗
Didn't you learn anything from our last go-round?
我猜没有
I guess not.
雷
Ray!
要怎么打开这个东西
How do you open this?
我猜这需要一组非对称密码
My best guess is it needs an asymmetric cipher.
你可以花五年时间用国安局级别的电脑破解
You can open it with five years and an NSA-grade computer.
不如现在就把他变大怎么样
What if we enlarged him now,
然后用他的体积来打破立方体
and then use his size to break the cube?
量子场无法穿透这种多聚体
The quantum field won't be able to penetrate this polymer.
知道吗  很遗憾你不能
You know, it is a shame that you won't live
活着看到我给这座城市  这个世界
to see the new life that I breathe into the city,
所注入的新生命
the new life that I breathe into this world.
你不会有机会的
You won't get the chance.
他们在我这里装了微型摄像头
They put mini-cams in here with me,
这些摄像头...
and those cameras...
必须从某处吸收能量
Need to draw power from somewhere.
雷  你是个天才
Ray, you are a genius.
我不知道我是不是天才  但我已经
Well, I don't know about that, but I have
吸取了足够能量来启动我的体外战衣
siphoned off enough juice to power up my exo-suit.
帕尔默博士的枪已经准备好了
Dr. Palmer's doo-hickey's ready.
希望你不介意我用技术术语
If you don't mind my use of a technical term.
开始
Do it!
我没死
I'm not dead.
我们救出雷了  走吧
We got Ray, let's go.
收到
Copy that.
莎拉
Sara!
不
No!
快  我们得走了
Come on. We have to go!
快点
Come on!
我们必须走了
We have to move.
很高兴见到你  雷
Good to see you, Ray.
衣服不错
Nice suit.
最糟糕的部分不是变小
The worst part wasn't being small--
而是周围的一切都变大了
it was that everything else was so big.
帕尔默科技的爆炸
The explosion at Palmer Tech
让我掉进了一个废弃的建筑工地
tossed me into an abandoned construction site.
蟑螂都有金毛猎犬那么大
The cockroaches were the size of golden retrievers.
我没夸张
I'm not exaggerating.
我们真的没必要知道这些
Uh, I think we don't need to know that, really.
我心里的昆虫学家对此很着迷
Ah, the entomologist in me was actually really fascinated.
你无法欣赏颚部的大小  直到...
I mean, you can't appreciate the size of the mandibles until the--
好吧  我不想听了
Mmm, mmm, no, I've heard enough.
我对蟑螂  蛇和蜘蛛反感极了
I got a thing against cockroaches, and snakes and spiders,
尤其是蟑螂
but especially cockroaches.
抱歉  雷
Sorry, Ray,
不是每个人都像你那样对虫子很热衷
not everyone shares your enthusiasm for bugs.
不过还好这个经历没有改变你
But it is good to see the experience didn't change you.
没错  你的体检报告出来了
Indeed. I got your medical tests back,
除了严重缺乏铁质
and aside from a very noticeable iron deficiency,
其他结果都良好
all your results are positive.
看来变小没有给你带来任何不良副作用
There don't seem to be any side effects from the, um, micro sizing.
听到这个真是松了口气
Relieved to hear it.
我们也是
So are we.
所以...这个要让我当他小白鼠的人是谁
So, this guy who wanted to make me his lab rat?
达米恩·达克
Damian Darhk.
我们相信"蜂群"这个组织以他为首
He's the leader of an organization we believe to be known as HIVE.
就像"幽灵"一样吗
Oh, like "Spectre?"
超酷
That's so cool!
也挺糟的
And terrible.
毋庸置疑  帕尔默
Be assured, Palmer,
假如他们想要你的科技
that if they wanted your tech,
肯定不会是拿去做好事
it wasn't for any good reason.
还有件事
One other thing--
他们听到了我给你的留言
they overheard my message to you.
我也有危险  我明白
I'm a possible target. I figured.
如果我无法面对大恶人的威胁
I wouldn't be doing this if I couldn't handle
我就不会一直干这事
being threatened by a super villain every now and then.
走吧  我送你回家
Come on. I'll take you home.
顺便让你掌握你公司的最新情况
I can catch you up on all the latest at your company.
事实上
Uh, actually,
在我决定"死而复生"前
until I decide to come back from the dead,
那还是你的公司
it's your company.
很好
Great.
搞什么鬼
What in the hell?!
你最好对那家伙的死有好的说辞
You better have a story to go along with that body.
西娅告诉我
Look, Thea told me
这是复活泉水的副作用
that this was a side effect of the Pit.
我以为我能与之对抗
And I thought that I could fight it.
但我却...
I just...
控制不住自己
I couldn't stop myself.
而最糟的是
And the worst part of it was,
我居然感觉好些了
I felt better.
莎拉  要控制住自己
Look, Sara, controlling this,
并不容易
it's not going to come easy, ok?
不是一朝一夕就能做到的
It's going to take you some time.
还要死多少人
And how many bodies?
西娅  我敬佩你的处理方式
Look, I respect the way that you could deal with this, Thea,
但我想以其他方式处理
but I need to handle this in a different way.
什么方式
Different how?
劳蕾尔  我欠你的实在太多了
Laurel, I owe you everything.
你给了我最好的礼物
You gave me the greatest gift that anyone ever could.
你给了我第二次机会
You gave me a second chance,
重新开始的机会
and the ability to start over.
我现在就该好好去把握它
I think it's time that I really do that.
但是莎拉...
But Sara--
你才刚刚回到我们身边
we just got you back.
莎拉  你不用离开
Sara, you don't have to leave.
我知道目前这看起来不可能
I know it doesn't seem possible right now,
但你是可以过上正常的生活
but you can have a normal life.
我的"正常生活"
It's been a long time since
已经很久没有正常过了
my normal has ever been normal.
我会去中城看看妈妈
Look, I'll go visit mom in Central City,
然后再去别的地方...
and then, somewhere...
也许会去很多地方
Maybe a few somewheres,
直到我把这事解决
just until I figure things out.
只要你确定那是你想要的
If you're sure that that's what you want to do.
这是你的人生
It's your life.
你要做让自己开心的事
And you have to do what makes you happy.
只是我会很想你的
I'm just really going to miss you.
我爱你  姐姐
I love you, sis.
一如既往  直到永远
Always and forever.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
雷怎么样了
How'd it go with Ray?
还好  直到我告诉他我把他的公寓卖了
Fine. Until I told him I sold his condo.
-我想...  -在我们...
- I wanted-- - Before we--
你先说
You go first.
不
No.
你先说
You.
我想我们应该...
I think we should...
好好谈谈
Clear the air.
我想谢谢你
I wanted to thank you.
帮忙救雷  而且还很谅解
For helping save Ray, and for being so understanding
那个处于小...
in the midst of my mini--
超大惊吓中的我
gargantuan freak out.
对不起  我不是个好的倾听者
Well, I'm sorry that I'm not the best listener.
但这一切对我而言...
But all of this is just, it--
还很新
it's kind of new to me.
对我也是
And to me.
我的父母没有给我树立
I didn't exactly grow up
拥有一段正常和健康关系的
with the best example of a normal,
好榜样
healthy relationship.
我的父母也没有
Line forms behind me.
我们能走到今天很不容易
It's kind of amazing that we've made it this far.
我们会好好的
We're going to be fine.
你为什么这么确定呢
How can you be so sure?
因为我们在彼此中找到了自我
'Cause we found ourselves in each other.
感到寂寞吗
Feeling lonely?
你应该没怎么经历过这种感觉吧
You don't even know the half of it.
也许我有
I might.
我来镇上探望我的女儿
I, um, I came to town to visit my daughter,
她却把我赶出她的公寓
but she kicked me out of her apartment
只为了结束跟我希望成为我女婿的人的斗争
to finish a fight with the man I hope will become my future son in law.
好了  该你说了
Ok, it's your turn.
我其中一个女儿刚回来不久
Well, one of my daughters is leaving town
又要离我而去了
after being back a whole five minutes.
听起来真该喝一杯
Sounds like a reason to drink.
我总是有喝一杯的理由
Oh, I always got a reason.
但我喝的是苏打汽水
But this is club soda.
昆汀
Quentin.
唐娜
Donna.
西娅  如果你哥哥过来
Hey, Thea. When your brother comes in,
能帮我拿这些给他签吗
could you have him sign these for me, please?
好的
Yeah.
你没事吧
You ok?
只是感到有点压力
Just a little stressed out.
也许...
Maybe, um...
也许我需要喝一杯
Maybe I need to get a drink.
虽然现在喝鸡尾酒有点早...
It's a little early for a cocktail, but...
不是现在  晚点怎么样
Not now. Later?
跟你一起去杰拉德喝
With you, at Gerard's?
我以为你...
But I thought you--
我只想过正常的生活
I just want to have a normal life.
八点在那里见吧
Meet me there at 8:00?
好的  没问题
Yeah, absolutely.
文件就交给你了
I'll leave these here.
帕尔默博士的分子重组
Dr. Palmer's molecular's realignment
依靠的是我们系统里的能量
was premised on a power draw from our system,
致使...
which resulted--
我搞得懂科学
Just because I understand science
不代表我对它有兴趣
doesn't mean I'm not bored by it.
扼要说明就好
Bottom line it for me.
我们提取了帕尔默博士
We were able to recover some residue
矮星合金制服的残留
from Dr. Palmer's Dwarf Star alloy,
将它做成了能量源
and use it to fashion into a power source.
很好
Good.
测试一下
Test it out.
用这个
On this.